{
  "typ": "qs",
  "questions": [
    {
      "type": "mc",
      "Question": "Which of these is not a loop?",
      "Options": [
        "count-controlled repetition",
        "post-test repetition",
        "expert system",
        "infinite repetition"
      ],
      "CorrectOption": 2
    },
    {
      "type": "mc",
      "Question": "A data type that contains upper case, lower case letters or numbers or punctuation. An ordered sequence of characters!",
      "Options": [
        "int",
        "str",
        "float",
        "bool"
      ],
      "CorrectOption": 1
    },
    {
      "type": "mc",
      "Question": "Which of these is not a valid way to describe an algorithm?",
      "Options": [
        "flowcharts",
        "persecode",
        "pseudocode",
        "plain English"
      ],
      "CorrectOption": 1
    },
    {
      "type": "mc",
      "Question": "What does SSD stand for?",
      "Options": [
        "Solid Disk Drive",
        "Solid State Drive",
        "Solid System Drive",
        "Service System Drive"
      ],
      "CorrectOption": 1
    },
    {
      "type": "bf",
      "Question": "What is 10010101 in denary?",
      "Answer": "149",
      "Answers": [
        "149"
      ]
    },
    {
      "type": "bf",
      "Question": "What is 11011001 in denary?",
      "Answer": "217",
      "Answers": [
        "217"
      ]
    },
    {
      "type": "bf",
      "Question": "What is 0xFA in binary?",
      "Answer": "11111010",
      "Answers": [
        "11111010",
        "1111 1010"
      ]
    },
    {
      "type": "bf",
      "Question": "What is 0xFE in denary?",
      "Answer": "254",
      "Answers": [
        "254"
      ]
    },
    {
      "type": "bf",
      "Question": "1100 1011 in hexadecimal is:",
      "Answer": "CB",
      "Answers": [
        "CB",
        "0xCB"
      ]
    },
    {
      "type": "bf",
      "Question": "The CPU stands for _____ _____ ____",
      "Answer": "central processing unit",
      "Answers": [
        "central processing unit"
      ]
    },
    {
      "type": "bf",
      "Question": "The RAM is the ______ _____ _____",
      "Answer": "random access memory",
      "Answers": [
        "random access memory"
      ]
    },
    {
      "type": "bf",
      "Question": "What is the less than or equal to operator in Python?",
      "Answer": "<=",
      "Answers": [
        "<="
      ]
    },
    {
      "type": "bf",
      "Question": "What is the greater than or equal to operator in Python?",
      "Answer": ">=",
      "Answers": [
        ">="
      ]
    },
    {
      "type": "mc",
      "Question": "In flowcharts, you would NOT see a diamond when trying to implement...?",
      "Options": [
        "selection",
        "condition controlled repetition",
        "a process",
        "count controlled repetition"
      ],
      "CorrectOption": 2
    },
    {
      "type": "bf",
      "Question": "When the number of bits reserved for the result of a calculation is not enough, it is called an ________.",
      "Answer": "overflow",
      "Answers": [
        "overflow"
      ]
    },
    {
      "type": "mc",
      "Question": "Not one of Santa's reindeer.",
      "Options": [
        "Cupid",
        "Donner",
        "Turing",
        "Vixen"
      ],
      "CorrectOption": 2
    },
    {
      "type": "bf",
      "Question": "What Python keyword would you use for repetition in Python?",
      "Answer": "while",
      "Answers": [
        "while",
        "for"
      ]
    },
    {
      "type": "bf",
      "Question": "Property of primary memory; it forgets data once it loses power:",
      "Answer": "volatile",
      "Answers": [
        "volatile"
      ]
    },
    {
      "type": "mc",
      "Question": "Which operator checks if two values are equal?",
      "Options": [
        "=",
        "==",
        "!=",
        "<>"
      ],
      "CorrectOption": 1
    },
    {
      "type": "mc",
      "Question": "Which of the following is the correct way to input a number in Python?",
      "Options": [
        "num = input",
        "num = (input)",
        "num = int(input())",
        "num = input()"
      ],
      "CorrectOption": 2
    },
    {
      "type": "mc",
      "Question": "Which of the following is the correct way to input a string in Python?",
      "Options": [
        "name = input",
        "name = (input)",
        "name = int(input())",
        "name = input()"
      ],
      "CorrectOption": 3
    }
  ]
}